Guide to the Clifton R. Merritt Papers 1935-2008
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
Clifton R. Merritt Papers
1935-2008
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 700
Merritt, Clifton R. (Clifton Reeve), 1919-2008
69.0 linear feet
This collection consists of the papers of environmental activist Clifton R. Merritt. From 1964 to 1978 Merritt served as Director of Field Services for The Wilderness Society. After leaving The Wilderness Society, Merritt founded the American Wilderness Alliance (later American Wildlands). His papers include correspondence, research files and other documents from his time with these agencies. Other materials cover his work with Montana Wilderness Association, Montana Wildlife Federation, and Friends of the Bitterroot. The collection also contains personal writings and correspondence.
Biographical Note
Clifton R. Merritt was born in November 1919 in the Prickly Pear Valley (now known as the Helena Valley) of Montana. He grew up on the cattle ranch his grandfather settled in the 1890s near the Gates of the Wilderness Mountains along the upper Missouri River. In his youth he was plagued by illness including polio and a triple heart valve leakage at age 15. Despite these physical ailments, Merritt was an avid hunter, fisherman, and hiker, often enjoying these activities with his twin brother, Don.
Clif attended college at Carroll College in Helena, Montana taking courses in liberal arts and sociology. After leaving Carroll, Merritt moved to Kalispell, Montana, and worked for the Bureau of Employment Security and Montana State Employment Service. He rose to Field Supervisor for the Bureau of Employment Security which involved hiring, training, and supervising of over 150 employees in nine (or more) field offices. Merritt held this position from 1953-1964.
During his time in Kalispell, Merritt helped found the Montana Wilderness Association in 1957. He also served in various positions for the Montana Wildlife Federation from 1950 to 1964. With these organizations, Merritt was a leader in getting the Montana Stream Preservation Act adopted and halting the establishment of the Spruce Park and Glacier View dams on the Flathead River, as well as spearheading the movement to get the 15,000 acre Jewel Basin Hiking Area established.
In 1964, Clifton Merritt became director of field services for The Wilderness Society. He began his work in Washington, DC, lobbying for the establishment of the Wilderness Act of 1964. Believing that the wilderness movement needed to garner the support of local citizens in order to add areas to the National Wilderness Preservation System, Merritt established The Wilderness Society’s Western Regional Office in Denver, Colorado, in 1966. In the Regional Office, Merritt trained and supervised a 15-person professional staff of natural resource specialists and field representatives stationed throughout the West. Through the efforts of Merritt and his staff, working closely with local groups, millions of acres were added to the National Wilderness Preservation System. Among those added were the Scapegoat, Absaroka-Beartooth, and River of No Return Wildernesses in Montana and the Weminuche, Flat Tops, and Eagles Nest Wildernesses in Colorado. After an organizational shakeup and upon hearing of the planned closing of the Regional Office, Merritt resigned from the Wilderness Society in 1978.
In 1979, Merritt, Sally Ranney, and Jerry Mallet, seeing a need left by the closing of The Wilderness Society’s Regional Office, formed The American Wilderness Alliance (known after 1983 as American Wildlands) based in Denver, Colorado. The organization worked with conservation groups throughout the Rocky Mountain West to preserve public lands for wildlife habitat and recreation. The American Wilderness Alliance was instrumental in getting the 161,000 acre Elkhorn National Wildlife Management Area established in Montana as well as ensuring the passage of the Colorado Wilderness Bill which gave wilderness designation to 1.4 million acres of public lands. In addition to serving as executive director, Merritt also edited the organization’s Wild America magazine and wrote and edited its On the Wild Side newsletter.
In 1984, Clifton Merritt returned to Montana and settled in the Bitterroot Valley. He still maintained the executive directorship of American Wildlands and the organization relocated to Bozeman, Montana, later that year. In 1990, Merritt stepped back from the executive directorship and became associate executive director. It was in 1990 that Merritt began the Corridors of Life Program. The Program used Geographic Information Systems to map wildlife migration corridors between roadless areas and established wilderness areas. As of 2009, American Wildlands’ Corridors of Life Program continues to work to restore and maintain wildlife corridors.
In 1998, at age 79, Clifton Merritt stepped down as associate executive director of American Wildlands. Though no longer in a leadership role at the organization, Merritt continued to support wilderness and environmental initiatives as a member of the organization he had helped found. He also continued to support local wilderness issues through membership with the organization Friends of the Bitterroot and continued membership with the Montana Wilderness Association and Montana Wildlife Federation.
Clifton Merritt had been a prolific writer all his life and his retirement afforded him more time for this interest. He began to pen his memoirs of the wilderness movement, which he titled Beyond the Roads. He also began work on a history of his grandfather’s settlement in the Prickly Pear Valley which he called I Remember my Grandfather. Merritt died on August 12, 2008 at the age of 89.
The Clifton R. Merritt Papers have been organized into seven series arranged by the periods in Merritt’s professional career. The majority of the series have been further subdivided into subseries, reflecting the order in which they were maintained by Merritt. The largest series in this collection relates to Merritt's time with American Wildlands and includes planning documents, committee minutes, and extensive correspondence files.
Of particular interest within this collection are documents and correspondence related to the recommendation of new wilderness areas into the National Wilderness Preservation System signed into law in 1964. The collection also contains documents related to the research and development of the Corridors of Life Program, which mapped wildlife migration corridors between roadless areas and established wilderness areas. The papers include a small portion of personal writings and correspondence including drafts and research for Merritt’s memoirs titled Beyond the Roads and his family history titled I Remember my Grandfather. The papers also contain awards and certificates received by Clifton R. Merritt.
This collection has been divided into seven series:
Series I: Montana Wildlife Federation, 1954-2004, .75 linear feet
Subseries 1: Administration, 1954-1999, 0.15 linear feet
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1953-2004, 0.5 linear feet
Subseries 3: Organizational Publications and Newsletters, 1956-2004, 0.10 linear feet
Series II: Montana Wilderness Association, 1949-2005, 1.25 linear feet
Subseries 1: Administration, 1968-2004, 0.25 linear feet
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1949-2004, 0.75 linear feet
Subseries 3: Organizational Publications and Newsletters, 1978-2005, 0.25 linear feet
Series III: The Wilderness Society, 1954-2000, 23.75 linear feet
Subseries 1: Administration, 1963-2000, 1.0 linear foot
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1954-1989, 22.70 linear feet
Series IV: American Wilderness Alliance/American Wildlands, 1957-2007, 29.5 linear feet
Subseries 1: Administration, 1965-2007, 5.0 linear feet
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1957-2007, 20.5 linear feet
Subseries 3: Corridors of Life Program, 1985-2006, 1.5 linear feet
Subseries 4: Organizational Publications and Newsletters, 1979-2007, 2.5 linear feet
Series V: Friends of the Bitterroot, 1991-2006, 0.5 linear feet
Series VI: Personal Materials, 1935-2007, 5.5 linear feet
Subseries 1: Writings and Files, 1935-2007, 2.5 linear feet
Subseries 2: Miscellaneous Materials, 1940-1998 and undated, 3.0 linear feet
Series VII: Awards, 1972-2007, 5.75 linear feet
Subseries 1: Subject Files and Correspondence, 1972-2007, 0.5 linear feet
Subseries 2: Certificates, Statuettes, and Plaques, 1976-2007, 5.25 linear feet
Series VIII: Photographs, unprocessed
Series IX: Motion Picture Films, approximately 1952-approximately 1977, 14 films
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
The collection was in the possession of Clifton R. Merritt and maintained at his home until his death in 2008. Merritt's daughter, Sherry Essig, maintained the bulk of the materials in Merritt’s home until their transfer to the Archives.
The collection was acquired by the Archives from Clifton R. Merritt’s daughter, Sherry Essig, in 2008.
Most bound monographs, congressional records, and published congressional reports were separated from the collection during processing.
In 2005 Robert N. Baker submitted a MA thesis to The University of Montana entitled Clif Merritt and Wilderness Wildlife: Learning How to Live in Paradise.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Merritt, Clifton R. (Clifton Reeve), 1919-2008--Archives; Ranney, Sally Ann; Cunningham, Bill
American Wilderness Alliance; American Wildlands (Organization); Friends of the Bitterroot; Montana Wildlife Federation; Montana Wilderness Association; Wilderness Society (U.S.)
West (U.S.)--Environmental conditions
Conservation of natural resources--Montana--Societies, etc; Conservation of natural resources--Montana--Bitterroot River Valley--Societies, etc; Conservation of natural resources--West (U.S.)--Societies, etc; Conservationists--West (U.S.)--Archives; Corridors (Ecology)--West (U.S.); Environmentalists--West (U.S.)--Archives; Wildlife conservation--West (U.S.)--Societies, etc; Wildlife conservationists--West (U.S.)--Archives
Photographs
Alaska; Idaho; Montana; Environmental Activism; Fisheries and Wildlife
- Montana Wildlife Federation, 1954-2004; Series I; 0.75 linear feet
  The Montana Wildlife Federation is a Helena, Montana, based organization dedicated to the preservation of wildlife habitat. Merritt served in various positions for the Montana Wildlife Federation from 1950 to 1964, and helped spearhead the movement to establish the Jewel Basin Hiking Area in Montana. This series is arranged into three subseries. Subseries 1, Administration, includes internal correspondence and memos. Subseries 2, Subject Files, consists of correspondence, reports, and news releases. Subseries 3 contains organizational publications and newsletters.
  - Administration, 1954-1999; Subseries 1; 0.15 linear feet
    - Flathead Lake Wildlife Association Memo, 1954 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Membership Mailer, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Memos and Internal Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Wildlife Legacy Council, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Subject Files, 1953-2004; Subseries 2; 0.5 linear feet
    - General Issue Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - General Issue Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - General Issue Correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Jewel Basin Hiking Area by Clifton Merritt, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Jewel Basin Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Flathead National Forest, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Lincoln Back Country, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Clifton Merritt, Editorials and Reports-Middle Fork of the Flathead, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Missouri River Breaks Wildlife Area, 1953-1964 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - News Releases, 1964 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - News Releases, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Wilderness Society, Correspondence-MATERIALS HAVE MOLD, SEE ARCHIVIST FOR ACCESS, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 124/1)
  - Organizational Publications and Newsletters, 1956-2004; Subseries 3; 0.10 linear feet
    - Flathead Outdoors, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Flathead Outdoors Clippings, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Flathead Outdoors Column, 1959-2006 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Montana Wildlife Federation News, 1963 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Montana Wildlife Newsletter, 1997-2004 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Montana Wildlife Newsletter, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Western Montana Wildlife News, 1956 (Box-folder 2/8)
- Montana Wilderness Association, 1949-2005; Series II; 1.25 linear feet
  Merritt helped found the Montana Wilderness Association (MWA) in 1957. The MWA is a Helena, Montana, based organization that works towards the preservation and designation of wilderness in Montana. Materials in this series related to the Glacier View and Hungry Horse Dams and the Wilderness Walks Program reflect these organizational goals. This series is arranged into three subseries: subseries 1: Administration, includes internal memos and correspondence as well as the organization’s constitution and bylaws. Subseries 2, Subject Files, consists of correspondence, reports and notes. Subseries 3 contains organizational publications and newsletters.
  - Administration, 1968-2004; Subseries 1; 0.25 linear feet
    - Constitution, Bylaws, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Constitution, Bylaws, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Interorganizational Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Missoula-Bitterroot Chapter, 1993 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Notices, Communiqués, Correspondence, 1997-2004 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Proposed Beartooth Wilderness-Meetings, 1968 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Subject Files, 1949-2004; Subseries 2; 0.75 linear feet
    - Cabinet Mountains Wilderness-Kootenai National Forest-Idaho Panhandle, 1967-1985 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Convention, 1978 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Dallas Eklund Award, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Doris Milner Special Conservation Award, 1975-1996 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Glacier National Park-Montana, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 3/9-11)
    - Glacier View Dam, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Hungry Horse Dams, 1949-1957 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Island Range Chapter Newsletters, 1999 and undated (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Ken and Florence Baldwin Special Conservation Award, Montana Wilderness Association, 1973-1998 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Legislating the Wild-A Guide to Montana Wilderness Legislation-Montana Wilderness Association, 1994 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Montana Wilderness Issues, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - National Wildlife Federation Conservation News, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Quiet Trails Montana, 1994 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Recreation Values, 1960 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Robert F. Cooney Special Conservation Award, 1994 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Smoky Range Dam, 1956 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Thurman Trosper Special Conservation Award, 1991-2001 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Wilderness Walks, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Wilderness Walks, 1997-2002 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Wilderness Walks, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Wilderness Walks, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Organizational Publications and Newsletters, 1978-2005; Subseries 3; 0.25 linear feet
    - Newsletters and Bulletins, 1978-2003 (Box-folder 4/15-16)
    - Wild Montana, 1996-2005 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Wild Montana, Letter Be Wild, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 5/2-3)
- The Wilderness Society, 1954-2000; Series III; 23.75 linear feet
  The Wilderness Society (TWS) is a national environmental organization dedicated to the preservation and designation of wilderness throughout the United States. In 1964, Clifton Merritt became director of field services for TWS. He began his work in Washington, DC, lobbying for the establishment of the Wilderness Act of 1964 and established the Society’s Western Regional Office in Denver, Colorado, in 1966. Of particular interest in this series are memos, notes, correspondence, and research done on areas proposed for entry in the National Wilderness Preservation System. This series has been divided into three subseries. Subseries 1, Administration, includes internal memos and correspondence, executive committee meeting notes and minutes, an organizational manual, and other notes. Subseries 2, Subject Files, consists of correspondence, notes, research files, and clippings.
  - Administration, 1963-2000; Subseries 1; 1.0 linear foot
    - Stewart Brandborg, 1976 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Bill Cunningham, Activity Reports, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Bill Cunningham, Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Development of Other Wilderness Support Groups, 1978 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Executive Committee Meetings, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Field Office Reorganization, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Field Office Reorganization, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Governing Council Meeting, 1978-2000 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Mailers and Memos to Membership, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Clifton Merritt, Notes, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Clifton Merritt, Statements, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Nevada Outdoor Recreation Association Grant, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Organization Manual, 1973 (Box-folder 6/6-7)
    - Zahniser, Craighead, Brandborg Correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Subject Files, 1954-1989; Subseries 2; 22.70 linear feet
    - Absaroka, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 6/9-11)
    - Absaroka Primitive Area-Gallatin and Custer National Forests, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 7/1-4)
    - Absaroka Primitive Area-Gallatin and Custer National Forests, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 7/5-7)
    - Absaroka-Beartooth Primitive Area Hearing Statements, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Absaroka-Beartooth Primitive Area Hearing Statements, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Absaroka-Beartooth Wilderness, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Absaroka-Beartooth-Slough Creek Primitive Area-Boulder River, Cooke City Road-Gallatin National Forest, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 8/2-4)
    - Alaska Bill-Admiralty Island National Preserve and Other, 1977 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Alaska Bill-Seward National Recovery Area and Other, 1977 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Alaska Coalition Fact Sheet-Land Ownership, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Alaska D-2 Hearings Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Alaska Fish and Wildlife General, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Alaska Maps, 1972 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - American Motors Conservation Awards, 1976 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Anaconda Pintler Wilderness-Beaverhead, Deerlodge, and Bitterroot National Forests, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 9/1-2)
    - Arguments for Wilderness, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Bear Trap Canyon Primitive Area-Dillon Bureau of Land Management, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Beartooth Plateau-Draft Environmental Statement, 1976 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Beartooth Primitive Area, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Beartooth Primitive Area-Gallatin and Custer National Forests, 1955-1976 (Box-folder 9/7-9)
    - Beartooth Ranch Acquisition-Montana Nature Conservancy, 1970 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Beartooth Reclassification Study Committee Final Report, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Beaverhead and Deer Lodge National Forests-Tobacco Roots-Middle Mountain Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Beaverhead National Forest, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 10/4-5)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-Anaconda-Pintler Enlargement-Wilderness Study Area, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-East Pioneer Wilderness Study Area, 1974 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-General Phase I, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 10/8-9)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-General Phase II, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-General Phase III, 1972-1987 (Box-folder 10/11-12)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-Land Use Planning, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-Snowcrest Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-West Pioneer Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 11/3-4)
    - Beaverhead National Forest-West Pioneer Proposed Wilderness Study Area, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Beaver-Marten-Vermillion Land Management Plan, 1979 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Bitterroot National Forest, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Bitterroot National Forest-General Phase I, 1972 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Bitterroot National Forest-General Phase II, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Bitterroot National Forest-General Phase III, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 12/2-3)
    - Bitterroot National Forest-Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Great Burn, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Bitterroot National Forest-Warm Springs, Medicine Tree, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Black Foot River-Alice Creek Proposed Wild and Scenic River, 1970 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Blue Joint Wilderness Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Bitterroot National Forest, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Blue Ribbon Streams Committee, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Bob Marshall Wilderness, 1965-1977 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Bob Marshall Wilderness-Clippings, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Bob Marshall Wilderness-Flathead and Lewis and Clark National Forests, 1963-1977 (Box-folder 12/11-12)
    - Bob Marshall Wilderness-Flathead and Lewis and Clark National Forests, Maps, undated (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Bob Marshall Wilderness-Sun Butte Dams, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Bowdoin National Wildlife Refuge-Proposed Wilderness, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Guy Brandborg, Forest Conservation, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Bull Lake-Napoleon, 1979 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Bull Mountain Area, 1971 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Bureau of Land Management Wilderness, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Canyon County Coalition, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Carter Administration Proposal-HR 39-Native Claims Act, 1977 (Box-folder 13/8-9)
    - Dick Carter, Wilderness Coordinator, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Castle Reef and Sun River Dams, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13/11-12)
    - Centennial Mountains Primitive Area-Dillon Bureau of Land Management, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Center for the Public Interest, Inc., 1963-1969 (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Charles M. Russell National Wildlife Range #1, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Charles M. Russell National Wildlife Range #2, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 14/2-4)
    - Charles M. Russell National Wildlife Range-Correspondence and Maps, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 14/5-6)
    - Cloud Peak, Popo Agie, and Seven Lakes-Wyoming, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Colorado Wilderness Bills and National Forest, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Colorado Forest Service Wilderness Bills-Indian Peaks, 1978 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Colorado Wilderness Study Act of 1975, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Congressional Record-Montana Wilderness Study Act, S. 393, 1975 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Congressional Statements, Clifton R. Merritt, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Continental Divide Trail, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Crazy Mountain Proposed Wilderness Study Area-Gallatin National Forest, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Custer National Forest, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Custer National Forest-General Phase I, 1972 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Custer National Forest-General Phase II, 1973 (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Custer National Forest-General Phase III, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Deerlodge National Forest-General Phase I, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15/12)